Ani Chavda

Lubbock, TX · anichavda
98@gmail.com · (214) 529-3209 · Anichavda.com

Summary

Currently working with Texas Tech Information Systems as a Programmer Analyst-3, I'm a seasoned Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience in Full Stack Development and leading products from conception to completion. Guided a team of 3 through 8+ product launches.

EXPERIENCE

Texas Tech University

Programmer Analyst 3

 $\begin{array}{c} \text{Lubbock , TX} \\ \text{May 2022 - Present} \end{array}$

- Analyzed user needs and software requirements to determine feasibility of design for over 8+ custom Full Stack projects and implemented solutions to meet the needs of university's programs and initiatives.
- Rewrote Functions, APIs and the queries of older projects to improve the efficiency by 40%.
- Wrote reusable components and libraries which helped the future projects decrease the overall development time by 30%.
- Wrote Automated test cases which reduced the user bug reports by 50%.

Texas Tech university

Research Assistant

Lubbock, TX Jan 2021 - May 2022

- Cleaned, Transformed and Combined data from many sources which reduced the manual load by 80%.
- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs.
- Developed complex SQL queries and calculated measures in Microsoft SQL and DAX respectively.
- Created Analytic Dashboard using Power-BI with integrated python prediction model.

Oracle India Pvt Ltd

Software QA

Gujarat , IN

June 2019 - Dec 2020

- Developed and maintained test strategy, test objectives, test plans, test cases, and test data.
- Created almost 400 automated test cases and test scripts after analyzing the requirements.
- Wrote APIs which improved the test runtime by almost 30%.
- Improved the first run pass rate from 60% to 95% by categorizing each test case.
- Created a web app to access HP ALM through REST API, reducing the run time by almost 90%.

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University

Lubbock, TX

MS Computer Science GPA: 3.5

Jan 2021 - May 2022

- Created fun projects like Decentralized Crowdfunding App on Ethereum Blockchain.
- Secured 100% Tuition waiver as part of the Research Assistantship.

GLS University

Gujarat , IN

BS Computer Application GPA: 4.0

May 2016 - May 2019

- Participated in Sports like Soccer and Cricket.
- Got 50% merit based scholarship.

SKILLS AND LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

- Skills : ReactJS, Angular, NodeJS, .NET, Oracle SQL, PL-SQL, Microsoft SQL, Web3, Solidity, PowerBI(DAX) , Jupyter, Appium and Selenium.
- Leadership: Currently part of the CORE Committee that helps improve employee communication, engagement and retention. Duties include Interviewing current employees, taking surveys, analyzing the responses and presenting the reports to the CIO of Texas Tech University for better decision making.